Finding Aid of America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee Record Group SR.198
State Archives of North Carolina
- Celebrations File, 1980-1987; SR.198.2; 198.2; 3690; Correspondence; 1.00; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources
  - British Library Exhibition (NC Museum of History): Miscellaneous, undated; SR.198.2.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder British Library Exhibition (NC Museum of History): Miscellaneous)
  - Commission on Indian Affairs, 1981-1987, undated; SR.198.2.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commission on Indian Affairs)
  - Committee Information and Minutes, 1982, undated; SR.198.2.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Committee Information and Minutes)
  - Cultural Events, 1980; SR.198.2.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Cultural Events)
  - Elizabethan Gardens: Correspondence, 1980-1987, undated; SR.198.2.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Gardens: Correspondence)
  - Elizabethan Gardens: Publications, undated; SR.198.2.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Gardens: Publications)
  - Elizabethan Rendezvous: Correspondence, 1981-1984; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Rendezvous: Correspondence)
  - Elizabethan Rendezvous: Programs and Brochures, 1984; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Rendezvous: Programs and Brochures)
  - Elizabethan Rendezvous: Project Description and Proposals, undated; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Rendezvous: Project Description and Proposals)
  - Elizabethan Rendezvous: Research Materials and Guides, undated; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Rendezvous: Research Materials and Guides)
  - English Speaking Union: Correspondence, 1979-1987, undated; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder English Speaking Union: Correspondence)
  - English Speaking Union: Memorandums, 1978, 1980-1987; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder English Speaking Union: Memorandums)
  - English Speaking Union: Miscellaneous, 1981, 1983-1984; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder English Speaking Union: Miscellaneous)
  - Folk life Programs, 1980; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Folk life Programs)
  - Funding and Grant Information, 1981, undated; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Funding and Grant Information)
  - Holgate, Jeanne: Lecture Transcript on John White Drawings, undated; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Holgate, Jeanne: Lecture Transcript on John White Drawings)
  - Madrigal Groups, 1980; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Madrigal Groups)
  - North Carolina Symphony, 1980; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder North Carolina Symphony)
  - Publications, 1978-1980, undated; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Publications)
  - Public Relations Program, 1982, undated; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Public Relations Program)
  - Roanoke Island Historical Association, 1937, 1980-1981; SR.198.2.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Roanoke Island Historical Association)
  - Shakespeare Festival, 1980; SR.198.2.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Shakespeare Festival)
  - Ship Feasibility Study, 1979-1980, undated; SR.198.2.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Ship Feasibility Study)
  - Status Reports, 1980; SR.198.2.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Status Reports)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: Multi-image Slide Program, 1983-1984; SR.198.2.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: Multi-image Slide Program)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: "Roanoke" Documentary Film, 1980-1982, undated; SR.198.2.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: "Roanoke" Documentary Film)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: WUNC-TV Chapel Hill Television Project, 1981-1985, undated; SR.198.2.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: WUNC-TV Chapel Hill Television Project)
  - Zoological Park (Asheboro), 1985-1987; SR.198.2.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Zoological Park (Asheboro))
- Archaeological File, 1980-1987; SR.198.3; 198.3; 4042; 1.00; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources
  Correspondences, research reports, grant proposals, legal agreements, summary reports, and memorandums consisting of information on various archaeological projects funded by the committee. Includes information on Algonkian Indians, maritime archaeology, and Fort Raleigh National Historic Site.
  RS No. 4042
  - Albemarle Archaeological Project and Agreement (Survey), 1987, undated; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Albemarle Archaeological Project and Agreement (Survey))
  - East Carolina University: Watts, Gordon P., Jr.: A Proposal to Search for the Site of Sir Walter Raleigh's Roanoke Colony, undated; SR.198.3.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Watts, Gordon P., Jr.: A Proposal to Search for the Site of Sir Walter Raleigh's Roanoke Colony)
  - Correspondences, 1980-1984, undated; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondences)
  - East Carolina University: Algonkian Indians, Correspondence, 1980-1985; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Algonkian Indians, Correspondence)
  - Hunter, Marvin R., "A Watery Fate for the Lost Colony," The State, September 1982; SR.198.3.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Hunter, Marvin R., "A Watery Fate for the Lost Colony," The State)
  - East Carolina University: Archaeological Agreements, 1983-1984, 1987, undated; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Archaeological Agreements)
  - East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: Archaeology and the Search for the First Carolinians: The Algonkian Indians, working draft, March 1985; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: Archaeology and the Search for the First Carolinians: The Algonkian Indians, working draft)
  - East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: The Carolina Algonkians, second draft, August 1985; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: The Carolina Algonkians, second draft)
  - East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: The Carolina Algonkians, final draft, January 1986; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: The Carolina Algonkians, final draft)
  - East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: Pomeiooc Site Correspondence, 1985-1987; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: Pomeiooc Site Correspondence)
  - East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: Pomeiooc Site Preliminary Report, 1986; SR.198.3.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Green, Paul R.: Pomeiooc Site Preliminary Report)
  - East Carolina University: Memorandums, 1984-1986; SR.198.3.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Memorandums)
  - East Carolina University: Phelps, David Sutton: Archaeological Salvage of an Ossuary at the Baum Site, October 1980; SR.198.3.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Phelps, David Sutton: Archaeological Salvage of an Ossuary at the Baum Site)
  - East Carolina University: Phelps, David Sutton: Archaeology of the Native Americans: The Carolina Algonkians, 1983-1984; SR.198.3.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Phelps, David Sutton: Archaeology of the Native Americans: The Carolina Algonkians)
  - East Carolina University: Phelps, David Sutton: Archaeology of the Tillet Site: The First Fishing Community at Wanchese, Roanoke Island, 1984; SR.198.3.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Phelps, David Sutton: Archaeology of the Tillet Site: The First Fishing Community at Wanchese, Roanoke Island)
  - East Carolina University: Underwater Archaeology Program, 1983-1987; SR.198.3.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina University: Underwater Archaeology Program)
  - Fort Raleigh National Historic Site: Archaeological Investigations, 1983-1984; SR.198.3.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Fort Raleigh National Historic Site: Archaeological Investigations)
  - Fort Raleigh National Historic Site: Correspondence, 1980-1983, undated; SR.198.3.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Fort Raleigh National Historic Site: Correspondence)
  - Fort Raleigh National Historic Site: Remote Sensing Project, 1984; SR.198.3.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Fort Raleigh National Historic Site: Remote Sensing Project)
  - Fort Raleigh National Historic Site: Resistivity Survey, 1984; SR.198.3.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Fort Raleigh National Historic Site: Resistivity Survey)
  - Historical Research Report Four Centuries and Roanoke Island: A Legacy of Geographical Change, by Bruce S. Cheeseman, September 1982; SR.198.3.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Historical Research Report Four Centuries and Roanoke Island: A Legacy of Geographical Change, by Bruce S. Cheeseman)
  - Memorandums, 1980, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.3.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Memorandums)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981, 1986, undated; SR.198.3.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Miscellaneous)
  - Secotan and Seco Archaeological Search, 1980; SR.198.3.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Secotan and Seco Archaeological Search)
- Newspaper Clippings File, 1980-1987, n.d.; SR.198.4; 198.4; S.38.5-7; Clippings Articles; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee
  Transferred According to Retention Schedule
  Processed, microfilmed
  North Carolina Collection, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill
  Transferred to Archives from the North Carolina Collection, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 6 December 2007.
  Newspaper clippings (compiled by a clipping service) which were housed originally in multiple volumes of three-ring binders along with two boxes containing a few magazines and loose newspaper clippings. The original clippings were received from the North Carolina Collection, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, where they had been sent for storage once the committee's office in Chapel Hill was closed. The processed materials were sorted and alphabetized by subject matter then pasted on ledger size paper in chronological order and microfilmed. The original clippings were destroyed after microfilming, and are contained on reels S.38.5-7.
  - Archaeology, 1981-1986, undated; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Archaeology)
  - Commemoration Events: Arrival of the First English Colony in America (Fort Raleigh National Historic Site), 26 June 1985; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration Events: Arrival of the First English Colony in America (Fort Raleigh National Historic Site))
  - Commemoration Events: British Library Exhibition at North Carolina Museum of History in Raleigh, March 8-June 6, 1985; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration Events: British Library Exhibition at North Carolina Museum of History in Raleigh)
  - Commemoration Events: Lighting of the Great Signal Fire to Sir Francis Drake (Hatteras Village), 10 June 1986; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration Events: Lighting of the Great Signal Fire to Sir Francis Drake (Hatteras Village))
  - Commemoration Events: Tours (England), April 1984; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration Events: Tours (England))
  - Commemoration Events: Tours (England), April-May 1987; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration Events: Tours (England))
  - Commemoration Events: Virginia Dare Birthday, 18 August 1987; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration Events: Virginia Dare Birthday)
  - County Commemorative Events: Committee Members, 1982; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder County Commemorative Events: Committee Members)
  - County Commemorative Events: County Events, 1982-1986; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder County Commemorative Events: County Events)
  - General Publicity, 1978-1987; S.38.5; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder General Publicity)
  - Elizabethan Gardens, 1986; S.38.6; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Gardens)
  - Elizabeth II Ship, 1979, 1981-1983; S.38.6; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabeth II Ship)
  - Elizabeth II Ship, 1984-1987; S.38.7; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabeth II Ship)
  - Native Americans, 1985-1986; S.38.7; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Native Americans)
  - Princess Anne Visitation, 1984; S.38.7; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Princess Anne Visitation)
  - Publications, 1982-1986, undated; S.38.7; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Publications)
  - Roanoke Mini-Series, 1985-1986; S.38.7; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Roanoke Mini-Series)
- Commemorative Events File, 1983-1987; SR.198.5; 198.5; 4043; 1.00; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources
  Correspondence, speeches, press kits, royal visit information, travel abroad information and other information related to all commemorative events held by AFHAC.
  RS No. 4043
  - Commemoration of the First Colony Landing 26 June 1585: General Correspondence, 1984-1985; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration of the First Colony Landing 26 June 1585: General Correspondence)
  - Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Invitation to President, 1980-1987; SR.198.5.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Invitation to President)
  - Press Kits, 1982-1983; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Press Kits)
  - Commemoration of the First Colony Landing 26 June 1585: Press Kit, 1985; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration of the First Colony Landing 26 June 1585: Press Kit)
  - Commemoration of the First Colony Landing 26 June 1585: Speeches, undated; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Commemoration of the First Colony Landing 26 June 1585: Speeches)
  - Drake's Visit (June 10, 1986), 1985-1986, undated; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Drake's Visit (June 10, 1986))
  - Elizabethan Gardens Luncheon: General Correspondence, 1985-1987, undated; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Gardens Luncheon: General Correspondence)
  - Elizabethan Gardens Luncheon: Invited Guests, August 1987; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Elizabethan Gardens Luncheon: Invited Guests)
  - Plymouth, England (TV Coverage Ceremonies), 1983-1984, undated; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Plymouth, England (TV Coverage Ceremonies))
  - Plymouth Historic Plaque, 1983, undated; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Plymouth Historic Plaque)
  - Royal Visit, 1980-1984, undated; SR.198.5.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Royal Visit)
  - Travel Abroad Planning: Academic Travel Abroad (Martha Henze), 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.5.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Travel Abroad Planning: Academic Travel Abroad (Martha Henze))
  - Travel Abroad Planning: Advisory Committee, 1981-1984, undated; SR.198.5.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Travel Abroad Planning: Advisory Committee)
  - Travel Abroad Planning: British Correspondence, 1981-1987; SR.198.5.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Travel Abroad Planning: British Correspondence)
  - Travel Abroad Planning: General Correspondence, 1986-1987, undated; SR.198.5.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Travel Abroad Planning: General Correspondence)
  - Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Budget and Financial Projections, SR.198.5.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Budget and Financial Projections)
  - Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Eighty-Second Airborne Division, 1985-1987, undated; SR.198.5.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Eighty-Second Airborne Division)
  - Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Fireworks Display, 1987, undated; SR.198.5.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Fireworks Display)
  - Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): General Correspondence, 1987, undated; SR.198.5.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): General Correspondence)
  - Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Memorial Regatta (Roanoke Island Yacht Club), 15 August 1987; SR.198.5.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): Memorial Regatta (Roanoke Island Yacht Club))
  - Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): North Carolina Symphony, 16 August 1987; SR.198.5.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare's Four Hundredth Birthday (18 August 1987): North Carolina Symphony)
- Logo File, 1983-1987; SR.198.6; 198.6; 4044; Agreements; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources
  Correspondence, licensing agreements, trademark registration, memorandums, and other information concerning the official logo of the America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (AFHAC).